(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
世界一？可愛い
Cutest in the world? Cute!
宇宙一？可愛い
Cutest in the universe? Cute!
もっともっと聞かせて
Let me hear it more and more!
ご褒美は…目を閉じて？
As a reward... close your eyes?
ちゅ
Chu!
見つけてくれてサンキュー
Thank you for finding me!
愛してくれてサンキュー
Thank you for loving me!
生き甲斐にしちゃってもいいのよ
It's okay to make me your reason for living!
一人じゃ無理だ 逆境
Adversity is impossible alone,
みんながいれば最強
but with everyone, I'm the strongest!
見つめ合ってよ 思い切り…
Let's gaze into each other's eyes... with all our hearts,
好きになっちゃえ！
and fall in love!
涙じゃ何も解決しないの分かってるから…だから
I know tears won't solve anything, so...
世界一？可愛い
Cutest in the world? Cute!
宇宙一？可愛い
Cutest in the universe? Cute!
もっともっと聞かせて
Let me hear it more and more!
よそ見はダメ！OK？
No looking away! OK?
瞬きも可愛い
Even my blinking is cute!
存在が可愛い
My very existence is cute!
もっともっと聞かせて
Let me hear it more and more!
ご褒美は… 目を閉じて…
The reward is... close your eyes...
ちゅ…
Mwah...
歌ってくれて サンキュー
Thank you for singing along!
笑顔くれて サンキュー
Thank you for the smiles!
生きててよかったって思った
I'm so glad I'm alive, I thought.
ちょっとのミスは愛嬌
A little mistake is just part of my charm!
だけどやる気は最強
But my motivation is the strongest!
競い合って 高め合って
Competing and improving together...
せーので 行こう！
On the count of three, let's go!
苦手からずっと逃げてちゃ
If you keep running from what you're bad at,
愛は届かないから
love will never reach you.
だから何度も 何度も挑もう
So let's challenge it again and again!
楽しんじゃおう！
Let's just have fun!
あざとくて 可愛い
Being calculatingly cute!
最高に 可愛い
Being the absolute cutest!
私だけを見ていて
Keep your eyes only on me!
よそ見はダメ！OK？
No looking away! OK?
瞬きも 可愛い
Even my blinking is cute!
存在が 可愛い
My very existence is cute!
もっともっと聞かせて
Let me hear it more and more!
輝くから 約束ね
I'll keep on shining, so promise me!
上手く歌えてるかな
I wonder if I'm singing well...
上手く踊れてるかな
I wonder if I'm dancing well...
間違うの怖くなるけど
I get scared of making mistakes, but...
できるできるできるできる そうだ！
I can do it, I can do it, yes!
信じてくれる人がいる
Because there's someone who believes in me!
この歌で君と繋がっていられる
This song keeps me connected to you!
忘れられないストーリー描いていこう
Let's keep writing an unforgettable story!
行くよ！
Here we go!
世界一！可愛い
The cutest in the world! Cute!
宇宙一！可愛い
The cutest in the universe! Cute!
もっともっと聞かせて
Let me hear it more and more!
よそ見はダメ！OK？
No looking away! OK?
瞬きも 可愛い
Even my blinking is cute!
存在が 可愛い
My very existence is cute!
もっともっと聞かせて
Let me hear it more and more!
ご褒美は 目を閉じて
The reward is... close your eyes...
ちゅ！
Mwah!
今日も鏡をチェック
Checking the mirror again today!
最高の笑顔届ける才能に
Even with a talent for delivering the best smiles,
甘えないの 努力が大事よ
I won't be complacent; effort is what matters!
ちゃんと お勉強して
Studying properly,
ちゃんと お片付けする
and tidying up properly,
だって私はアイドルだもん
because I'm an idol, after all!
好きなタイプは私
My favorite type is 'me'!
大好きで マジ一途な人
Someone who loves me and is truly devoted!
ぴったりの君だけど 今じゃない
You're a perfect match, but not right now!
ナンバーワンはもっと先だけど
Becoming number one is still a way off, but...
君だけのものに なれないの ああごめん
I can't belong to you alone, oh, I'm sorry!
いつまでも好きでいて 約束よ
Please love me forever, it's a promise!
わがままなお願いね みんなのものでいたい
A selfish request, isn't it? I want to belong to everyone!
それでも私のこと 好きですか？
Even so, do you still love me?
ピンク色のフリフリ
Pink frilly clothes,
スポットライト浴びて
bathed in the spotlight,
いつかきっとね 君だけの私に
someday I'll surely be yours alone.
今はもっと歌いたい
But for now, I want to sing more!
現役アイドルちゅ〜
Active Idol Chu~!
ずっとワクワクなのよ
I'm always so excited
握手会もして
Having handshake events
お気に入りパクしちゃうんだ
And snatching up my favorites
キラキラメイクは今日もバッチリ
My sparkly makeup is perfect again today
やっと君と出会えた
I finally got to meet you
ちょっと話せるだけなのになんか
Even though we only talk for a bit, somehow...
明日はもっと早起きして
Tomorrow, I'll wake up even earlier
2人の時間を楽しみにしてるから
Because I'm looking forward to our time together
握手会、コンサート 会いに来て
Handshake events, concerts, come see me
君のハッピーなその顔
That happy face of yours,
ずっと覚えているわ
I'll remember it forever
今週も来週も会いたいな
I want to see you this week and next week too
おしゃれなお洋服も
I'll prepare some stylish clothes
準備して待ってるね
And be waiting for you
愛のこもった頑張る君の姿は
Your hardworking figure full of love,
いつまでも好きでいる
I'll always love it
オフィシャル両想い
Official Mutual Love
私と巡り合えた一人にありがとう
Thank you to the one person who found me
こんなにキュートな私になっちゃうもん
It makes me feel so cute
クルクル回る雲きらり回ってる
The spinning clouds are shining as they turn
いくつになってもこのまま ここで輝く
No matter how old I get, I'll keep shining here
ねえねえ教えて 夏色、今日も可愛い？
Hey, hey, tell me, is Natsuiro cute today too?
可愛いよー！
You're cute!
いつまでも好きでいて 約束よ
Please love me forever, it's a promise
私だって君のこと ずっとずっと大好き
Because I love you so, so much too
一生私のこと好きですか？
Will you love me for a lifetime?
ピンク色のフリフリ スポットライト浴びて
In my pink frills, bathed in the spotlight
いつかきっとね 君だけのお姫様に
Someday, surely, I'll be your princess
今はまだ歌いたい 現役アイドル中
For now, I still want to sing as an active idol
わー！
Waaaah!
みんな！せーの、こんばんわっしょーい！
Everyone! One, two, Konban-wasshoi!
どうもホロライブの清楚担当
Hello, I'm the one in charge of purity in Hololive...
みんなのアイドル、夏色まつりです！
everyone's idol, Natsuiro Matsuri!
ということで今年もやってきました
And so, it's that time of year again
遅ればせながらの生誕誕生祭でございますよ
It's my somewhat belated birthday celebration!
まつりちゃんの誕生日は7月22日、なんです、が
Matsuri-chan's birthday is July 22nd, but...
ま、あの周年が6月ということで
well, since my anniversary is in June...
毎年11月にやらしていただいております
I hold it every year in November
なので今日も実質誕生日でございますね
So today is practically my birthday too!
はい。おめでとう。ありがとうございます
Yes. Happy birthday! Thank you very much
そして本日のハッシュタグはこちら！ドドドドドン！
And here's today's hashtag! Drumroll please...
夏色まつり生誕祭2025でございます
It's Natsuiro Matsuri Birthday Festival 2025!
いっぱいツイートしてトレンドに入れてあげてください
Please tweet a lot and get it trending
お願いします
I'm counting on you!
あのスクショとかもね、あの撮っていただいたりとか
Please take screenshots and everything,
あとツイートしてくれたら、まつりちゃんが後で
and if you tweet them, Matsuri-chan will...
エゴサーチさせていただきますので、ぜひよろしくお願いしますね
ego-search for them later, so please do!
見ちゃうよ見ちゃうよ
I'll be watching, I'll be watching!
はい。そしてね、ま、皆さんもお気づきかなと思います
Yes. And, well, I think you've all noticed...
本日のタイトル、アイドル革命進行中！
Today's title: Idol Revolution in Progress!
今日の主役は夢の途中というタイトルにもあるように
As the title 'Today's Protagonist is Mid-Dream' suggests,
本日はアイドルさんの曲をたくさん詰め込んだ
Today is filled with many idol songs,
超とってもとっても可愛くてポップでキュートで
making it a super, super cute, pop, and adorable...
ワクワクするようなライブになっていますので
and exciting live performance,
最後まで楽しんでいってくださいね
so please enjoy it until the very end!
よろしくお願いします
Thank you for joining me!
コメントでもサイリウムを振ったりとか
Please wave your lightsticks in the comments,
可愛いよーって言っちゃったりとか、たくさんしてくださいね
and say things like 'You're cute!' as much as you want!
ということでこの後は皆さんお待ちかねのゲストパート！
And now, it's time for the guest part you've all been waiting for!
やったー！
Yay!
はい。ちょっとね、あの…まつりちゃん、
Yes. Well, you see... Matsuri-chan,
本気ダンスとかが、すごーく大好きなので、
really, really loves serious dancing,
レッスンで「おねがい、やらせてください！」って言って、
so in the lessons I said, "Please! Let me do it!"
フォーメーションとかもね、含め、みんなには頑張ってもらっていますので、
including the formation and everything, everyone is working hard,
あの、君の推しがもしいたら、褒めてあげてください。
so if your favorite is there, please praise them.
ということで、ゲストパート準備してきちゃいますね！
With that, I'm going to get ready for the guest part!
じゃあみんな「わくわく」ってコメントして待ってて。
So everyone, wait while commenting "waku-waku" (excited)!
じゃあ、いってきまーい！
Well then, I'm off-mai!
わくわく、わくわく、わくわくわくわくわくわく…
Waku-waku, waku-waku, waku-waku waku-waku...
Hey yo, D.E.M.P.A from Akihabara to everywhere
さあさあ寄ってらっしゃい見てらっしゃい
Come on, come on, step right up and see
もう一切合切やっちゃいな
Just do it all, everything and anything
ありったけのカワイイと楽しい事詰め込んで
Pack it full of all the cute and fun things you can
さあ少年少女よ船に乗っていざ出航じゃ
Come on, boys and girls, get on the ship and set sail
Hey yo, D.E.M.P.A from Japanese Heart area
みんな元気ですか？声聞かせて！
Is everyone doing well? Let me hear your voices!
はい、でんぱ！でんぱ！
Yes, Dempa! Dempa!
ありがとう！準備はバッチリのようね
Thank you! Looks like you're all perfectly prepared
OK!
今からデッカい船に乗っていざ出航じゃ
From now, get on the big ship and set sail
さあみんな
Come on, everyone
DANCE DANCE DANCE
帆を張って ヒラリヒラリ
Set the sails, fluttering, fluttering
かっこつけてパッパッパッ
Striking a pose, pa-pa-pa
飛び出てドーン
Bursting out, boom!
むちゃくちゃな助言見たり
Seeing crazy advice
それが僕らにとってのファンタジー
That's a fantasy for us
祝え 祝え 感じるんだ 酔ってるんだ
Celebrate, celebrate, feel it, swaying
ソレ ソレ ソレ ソレ！
Sore sore sore sore!
SHAKE SHAKE SHAKE
胸張っては焦ったり
Puffing out chest, then hurrying
ずっと知ってもこっちこっちこっち
Even knowing all along, this way, this way, this way
逆方向
Opposite direction
青春はそれでいいのだ
Youth is fine like that
勘違いも味方にしちゃうのだ
Making even misunderstandings our allies
新版書 偉大日本 踊れ日本
New edition, Grand Japan, dance Japan
あーそれそれそれ よいしょ！
Ah sore sore sore, heave-ho!
珍走電車とどこまでも
With the rare train to anywhere
ほらパワフル全開で突き抜けろ
Look, break through with full power
あっちもこっちもこっちも祭りだわっしょい
Here and there and everywhere, it's a festival, wasshoi
あっぱれあっぱれアドベンチャー
Splendid, splendid adventure
大和撫子絵巻物
Yamato Nadeshiko picture scroll
不思議な言霊
Mysterious power of words
はいはい！
Yes, yes!
奇想天外さいつまでも
Fantastic and bizarre forever
神様仏様うさぎ様
Gods, Buddhas, and Rabbits
月に祈って拝んで火を持って
Praying to the moon, worshipping, holding fire
半端な気持ちを断ち切って
Cutting off half-hearted feelings
とりあえず生様でついてこい
For now, follow me with your way of life
Follow me!
あー 君の未来を明るく照らすなんてお茶の子さいさいさい！
Ah, your future will be brightly lit, it's a piece of cake!
百花繚乱 大和撫子たちよ
Blooming profusely, Yamato Nadeshikos
どでかい花火を上げましょね
Let's set off a giant firework
ほら踊る阿呆に見る阿呆
Look, dancing fools and watching fools
同じ阿呆なら踊らにゃ損損
If we're both fools, you lose if you don't dance
それそれ！
Sore sore!
DANCE DANCE DANCE
ほらしまって おへそチラリ
Look, tuck it in, a peek at the navel
靴脱いだら即即即 破れてる
If you take off your shoes, they're immediately torn
ドタバタなこのステージ
This frantic stage
それが私にとっての正義
That's justice for me
いっそう尊い羽ばたくんだ聞こえるんだ
More precious than ever, I'll spread my wings, I can hear it
それそれそれそれ！
Sore sore sore sore!
SHAKE SHAKE SHAKE
胸張って涙キラリ
Puffing out chest, a glint of a tear
強がってもキュンキュンキュン苦しいの
Even if I act tough, it's tight and painful
乙女はそれでいいのだ
A maiden is fine like that
マイナスも味方にしちゃうのだ
Making even negatives our allies
常恒愛してる みんな大好き
Love you deeply, love everyone
Da-da-da-da-da BREAKDOWN!
よー、はい！
Yo, hai!
珍走電車とどこまでも
With the rare train to anywhere
ほらパワフル全開で突き抜けろ
Look, break through with full power
あっちもこっちもこっちも祭りだわっしょい
Here and there and everywhere, it's a festival, wasshoi
あっぱれあっぱれアドベンチャー
Splendid, splendid adventure
大和撫子絵巻物
Yamato Nadeshiko picture scroll
不思議な言霊
Mysterious power of words
それ！
Sore!
奇想天外さいつまでも
Fantastic and bizarre forever
神様仏様うさぎ様
Gods, Buddhas, and Rabbits
月に祈って拝んで火を持って
Praying to the moon, worshipping, holding fire
半端な気持ちを断ち切って
Cutting off half-hearted feelings
とりあえず生様でついてこい
For now, follow me with your way of life
Follow me!
あー 君の未来を明るく照らすなんてお茶の子さいさいさい！
Ah, your future will be brightly lit, it's a piece of cake!
よー、はい！
Yo, hai!
満月の下で踊りましょ
Let's dance under the full moon
サクラ舞い散る季節歌いましょ
Let's sing in the season of falling cherry blossoms
君といつかまた出会うその日まで
Until that day we meet again sometime
それ 地球様も 太陽様も 八百万様も あなた様も
Even Mother Earth, the Sun, the Myriad Gods, and You
ワン・ナイト・エンド・バイ・でんぱい・パイ・さよなら
One Night End Bye Dempai-pai Sayonara
バイバイ！
Bye bye!
逃げない!!
Nigenai!!
時間経てば事務的に
Time passes and it comes routinely
やってくる
And it just keeps coming
明日なんて
Tomorrow isn't
我々の明日じゃない
our tomorrow
逃げたい じゃあどこに
I want to run away, well then to where?
逃げればいいのかな
Should I just run away?
曖昧な場所では
In this ambiguous place,
何にも変われない
nothing can change
立ち向かえとか
Words like "face it"
やり直せるよとか
or "you can start over"
間違った道を
Restart the wrong path
何度もやり直させる
making me do it over and over
あなた一体誰ですか？
Who on earth are you?
論点ずれてる
Pushing aside those
人達なんか押し除けて
who are missing the point
自分の道作らなくちゃ
I have to make my own way
“失敗しない”なんて契約を人は
No one has ever made a contract
誰とも結んではいない
saying "I won't fail"
“幸せになります”とは皆いつか
“I will be happy” is a promise
大事な人と約束したはずだ
everyone made to someone important
大人になるために
In order to become an adult
早く忘れることだけ覚え
learning only how to forget quickly
無理に目を背けたら
If you look away by force,
10年後の子供を救えないよ
you can't save your future self in 10 years
全部自分が悪いと
To you, who blames yourself
責める君に伝えたい
for everything, I want to tell you
同じ言葉を人に
No one can blame you,
言わない君を誰も責められない
who doesn't say the same words to others
逃げない じゃあどこに
I won't run away, well then where...
向かえばいいのかな
...should I head to?
辛さの根源を
The source of the pain,
見つめ直せる場所
a place where I can re-examine
いきなり空を飛ぶ
I don't know how to fly
方法なんて知らない
in the sky all of a sudden
悪と暇の行き来は
Nobody go back and forth between
誰ももうしないで！
evil and leisure anymore!
生きろとか蘇れとか
Words like "live" or "be resurrected,"
もういい もういい 逆に逃げて
enough already, enough, actually run away
もういいんだよとかいう
Saying "it's okay to do so,"
私は一体誰ですか？
who on earth am I?
わかってくれている
The sparkle in the eyes
瞳の輝きが
that understand
消えてないって証明してくれた
There are people who proved
人達がいる
that it hasn't disappeared
時間経てば事務的に
Time passes and it comes routinely
やってくる
And it just keeps coming
明日なんて
Tomorrow isn't
我々の明日じゃない
our tomorrow
足に訊ねる 走れるか
Asking my legs "can you run?"
指に訊ねる 開けるか
Asking my fingers "can you open it?"
体温に訊ねる 血潮で導いて
Asking my body temperature, "lead me with my blood"
いけるだろうか
Can I make it?
始まりの合図は他の
I don't want to let anyone else
誰にも決めさせたくない
decide the signal to start
教科書の先の現代は
The modern era beyond the textbooks,
我々が作ってゆくから
we will create it ourselves
だから逃げない
So I won't run away,
私は逃げない
I won't run away
逃げたい君を
You who want to run away,
置いてはゆかない
I won't leave you behind
じゃなきゃ意味ない
Otherwise it's meaningless,
離したことない
I've never let go
顔を見なくなって
Even if I stop seeing your face,
君を知ってる
I know you
苦しめる渦の中
In the middle of the painful vortex,
頭脳の目広げて
open the eyes of your brain
別の角度で見てごらん
Look at it from a different angle,
そこだけ逃げないで
don't run away from just that
時間経てば事務的に
Time passes and it comes routinely
やってくる
And it just keeps coming
明日なんて
Tomorrow isn't
我々の明日じゃない
our tomorrow
とくべチュ、して
Toku-bechu, shite
「とくべチュ、して？」
"Give me a special kiss?"
Oh baby「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, 'I love you' isn't enough
一番　大事がいい
I want what's most important
君が作るオリジナルの
Your original...
特別、チューして。
special kiss.
眩しくて目が覚めて
Dazzled, I wake up
愛おしく思ってよ
Think of me dearly
眠り姫のように優しく口付けて
Gently kiss me like a Sleeping Beauty
ゴミめいたこの世界
In this world that's like trash
ピュアがかかる君がいる
There you are, covered in purity
全てに触れずに二人だけでいよう
Let's be just the two of us, touching nothing else
私のこと独占して
Monopolize me
君だけのモノになってもいい
It's okay to become yours alone
なんでもある日の
Even on an ordinary day
「なんでもない」気付いてね
Please notice it's 'not just anything'
Oh baby「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, 'I love you' isn't enough
君の「特別」にして
Make me your 'special' one
ねえ　もっと　Give me a kiss もう私は
Hey, more, give me a kiss, I'm already...
君でいっぱいよ
full of you
ほどけないリボン結び
An unraveled ribbon knot
小指ギュッて縛って
Tie my pinky tight
そうよ一生一緒がいいもん
That's right, I want to be together for life
とくべチュが欲しい
I want a special kiss
二人きり週末は
A weekend with just the two of us
奏でてよハーモニー
Play our harmony
流れ星見たら私を想ってほしい
When you see a shooting star, I want you to think of me
あまあまな君なのに
Even though you're so sweet
広い街吸い込まれ
Sucked into the big city
戦う姿に大きいなはなまるだね
Your fighting figure gets a big gold star
好きなところ、優しいとこ。
What I like, your kindness.
嫌いなとこも優しいとこ。
What I hate, also your kindness.
誰にもあげない
I won't give you to anyone
私だけ独り占め！
I'll keep you all to myself!
う〜　だって今までの人と
Ooh~ because compared to people I've known until now...
同じはいらないんです
I don't need the same thing
ねえもっと　Give me more love 私のため
Hey more, give me more love, for my sake
生きてほしいんです
I want you to live
だからウサギと私は
So like a rabbit, I...
寂しくさせないで
Don't let me be lonely
そんなんじゃ束縛じゃないわ
That's not enough to be called restraint
苦しいのが好き
I like it when it's painful
ショートケーキ　イチゴみたいに座ってもいい？
Can I sit on a shortcake like a strawberry?
赤く甘い恋だもん
It's a red, sweet love
誰かにあげた「大好き」も
The 'I love you's you gave to someone else
返してもらって全部私に
Get them back and give them all to me
ちょーだい　もっと！
Give it to me, more!
君は神様が作る
You are a person made by God
奇跡のようなヒト
Like a miracle
拗ねた顔もその寝顔も
That sulking face, and that sleeping face...
守ってあげるね
I'll protect them for you
Oh baby「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, 'I love you' isn't enough
君の「特別」にして
Make me your 'special' one
ねえ　もっと　Give me a kiss もう私は
Hey, more, give me a kiss, I'm already...
君でいっぱいよ
full of you
ほどけないリボン結び
An unraveled ribbon knot
小指ギュッて縛って
Tie my pinky tight
ねえ baby 最初で最後の
Hey baby, for the first and last time...
とくべチュにしてね
give me a special kiss
ミルクで乾杯！
Cheers with milk!
お砂糖混ぜたら甘い
Sweet when sugar is mixed in
レンジでチンしてあったかい
Warm after being microwaved
レッツゴー　ぱぴぷぺPOP
Let's go, Papi Pupe POP
よー　人生万歳！
Yo, hurray for life!
この先10年安泰！
Peace of mind for the next 10 years!
盛れてバズったらはんぱなーい
It's amazing if you look good and go viral
レッツゴー　ぱぴぷぺPOP
Let's go, Papi Pupe POP
ぱぴぷぺPOP
Papi Pupe POP
ポッピーハッピー
Poppy Happy
ぴょんぴょんです　びゅんびゅんです　るんるんです　ピカピカです　ハッピーです
Boing-boing, zoom-zoom, humming, sparkling, happy
問題ないっす　半端ないっす　我らディスコティックなバンビーナ
No problem, incredible, we are discotheque bambinas
テキトーです　イージーです　曖昧です　ずっとこうやって
Carefree, easy, ambiguous, let's keep going like this
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じでポップに生きていこう
With a Papi Pupe Po feeling, let's live poppingly
ぱぴぷぺPOP
Papi Pupe POP
Hi! Hi!
ぱぴぷぺPOP
Papi Pupe POP
Hi! Hi!
毎日毎日パーティピーポー　Let me yeah! dancin'
Every day party people, let me yeah! dancin'
横ノリ　縦ノリ　悪ノリで　Oh yeah!
Side sway, vertical jump, getting rowdy, oh yeah!
映画のキャストみたいに　ボンキュのボンな美ボディ
Like movie cast members, curvaceous beautiful bodies
弾けて　smile delight
Burst open, smile delight
なんでスネてんの？（うるさい！）
Why are you sulking? (Shut up!)
なんで泣いてんの？（あっちいって！）
Why are you crying? (Go away!)
なんで なんで？
Why, why?
だって だって 女の子だもん
Because, because I'm a girl
なんで帰っちゃうの？
Why are you going home?
（触んないで！）
(Don't touch me!)
なんで怒ってんの？
Why are you angry?
あーんもう
Ahn, geez
わかってよ 言わなくてもわかってよ
Understand me, understand me even if I don't say it
どうして？ あ、ごめん やっぱ好きー！
Why? Oh, sorry, I actually love you!
めんどくさっ
How troublesome
ぴゅんぴゅんです ぴゅんぴゅんです
It's Pyun-pyun, it's Pyun-pyun
るんるんです きゃっきゃーです ハッピーです
It's Run-run, it's Kya-kya, it's happy
問題ないっす ハンパないっす 我々ディスコティックなバンビーナ
No problem, it's incredible, we're discotheque bambinas
テキトーです イージーです 曖昧です ずっとこうやって
We're casual, it's easy, it's vague, staying like this forever
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで
With a Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe-Po feel
POPに生きていこう
Let's live poppingly
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
Hi! Hi! Hi!
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
Hi! Hi! Hi!
ぱっと咲いて shy
Blooming suddenly and shy
ピアニシモで kiss
Kissing with pianissimo
プロいラップよ
A professional rap
ペプシ飲んで「お～」
Drink Pepsi and go "Oh~"
ポップに踊ろう
Let's dance poppingly
さぁ Let's, さぁ Let's go!
Now let's, now let's go!
Funny Funny time!
ぺっぺけぺっぺ ぺっぺけぺっぺ
Pe-peke-pe-pe, pe-peke-pe-pe
きゅんです3・2・1
Kyun-desu 3, 2, 1
ぺっぺけぺっぺ ぺっぺけぺっぺ
Pe-peke-pe-pe, pe-peke-pe-pe
おこです3・2・1
Oko-desu 3, 2, 1
ぺっぺけぺっぺ ぺっぺけぺっぺ
Pe-peke-pe-pe, pe-peke-pe-pe
笑顔で3・2・1
Smile 3, 2, 1
ぺっぺけぺっぺ ぺっぺけぺっぺ
Pe-peke-pe-pe, pe-peke-pe-pe
変顔3・2・1
Funny face 3, 2, 1
なんかいい感じ
Something feels good
もしもしー？
Hello?
なんか嬉しいね
I'm somehow happy
どうしたん
What's up?
なんか なんか やっぱ やっぱ 女の子だもん
Somehow, somehow, as expected, as expected, I'm a girl
なんかハッピーです
I'm somehow happy
うん。それな
Yeah, I know
なんか頂点です
I'm somehow at the top
あーんもう
Ahn, geez
幸せです！聞いてよ幸せです ちょっと話してっからさ聞いてー！
I'm happy! Listen, I'm happy, I'm talking so listen!
へー そうなんだ...
Oh, is that so...
最高です 絶好です
It's the best, it's perfect
ミラクルです 雲の上です ハイパーです
It's a miracle, it's above the clouds, it's hyper
とんでもないっす 尋常ないっす 我々アーティスティックなバンビーナ
It's outrageous, it's extraordinary, we're artistic bambinas
ちょっとだけ 素ボクラです
Just a little, we're our true selves
大概です ずっとこうやって
It's mostly, staying like this forever
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで
With a Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe-Po feel
POPに生きていこう
Let's live poppingly
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
ミルクで乾杯 砂糖混ぜたらあまーい
Toast with milk, it's sweet when you mix in sugar
レンジでチンしてあったかーい Let's Go ぱぴぷぺぽ
Heat it in the microwave and it's warm, Let's Go Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe-Po
ヨー！人生万歳 この先10年安タイ
Yo! Long live life, peace for the next 10 years
惚れてバズったらはんぱなーい Let's Go ぱぴぷぺぽ
It's incredible if you fall in love and go viral, Let's Go Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe-Po
ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po, Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ Poppin'!
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po, Pa-pi-pu-pe-po, Poppin'!
ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po...
愛チュセヨ Lovin' you アモーレ アミーゴ
Ai chuseyo, Lovin' you, amore, amigo
ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po...
A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P
People! People!
Be Poppin'! Be Poppin'!
ぱ ぱ ぱ ぱ ぱー！
Pa pa pa pa paa!
最大級 最高級 最上級 ハイスペックな人生です
It's a maximum, top-class, highest-grade, high-spec life
アイラビュー アイフォーユー だけど君がいないと寂しいな
I love you, I for you, but it's lonely without you
本当はね やっぱりね 結局ね ずっとこうやって
Actually, as expected, in the end, staying like this forever
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで
With a Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe-Po feel
POPに生きていたい
I want to live poppingly
ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
ぴゅんぴゅんです ぴゅんぴゅんです
It's Pyun-pyun, it's Pyun-pyun
るんるんです きゃっきゃーです ハッピーです
It's Run-run, it's Kya-kya, it's happy
問題ないっす ハンパないっす 我々ディスコティックなバンビーナ
No problem, it's incredible, we're discotheque bambinas
テキトーです イージーです 曖昧です ずっとこうやって
We're casual, it's easy, it's vague, staying like this forever
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで
With a Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe-Po feel
POPに生きていこう
Let's live poppingly
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで POPにエンジョイ
With a Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe-Po feel, enjoy poppingly
あれ これ どれ それ 楽しいね ハイハイ！
That, this, which, that, it's fun! Hi-hai!
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで POPにエンジョイ
With a Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe-Po feel, enjoy poppingly
あれ これ どれ それ 楽しいね ハイハイ！
That, this, which, that, it's fun! Hi-hai!
ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po...
Poppin', POP!
みんなー ゲストパートどうだったー？
Everyone, how was the guest part?
かーわいかったー？ ありがとうございます！
Was it cute? Thank you very much!
ということでね、すごい続けてやってしまったんですが、
And so, we did them all in a row,
まず『Sakura Apparition』はAZKiちゃんとルーナちゃんとリリカに出てもらいました。
First, for "Sakura Apparition," I had AZKi-chan, Luna-chan, and Ririka join me.
なんかすごい「サクラ」というか春っぽいね、ピンクーな感じのメンバーを呼びました。
I invited members who give off a real "Sakura" or spring-like, pink feeling.
リリカすごい頑張ってたよなぁ、
Ririka really worked hard, didn't she?
すごいね練習中も「あぁ～できない～！」って言いながら頑張ってたリリカ。
Even during practice, she was saying "Ah, I can't do it!" while doing her best.
そして次『逃げない』ね。
And next was "Nigenai".
『逃げない』はちょっと結構古めの曲なんですけど、
"Nigenai" is a bit of an older song,
まつりがすごいすごい大好きで、一番推していた、ゆるめるモ！さんの楽曲で、
but it's a song by You'll Melt More!, whom Matsuri loves so very much and was a huge fan of.
あのー、ここで歌えて、すごく嬉しかったです。ありがとうございますね。
I was so happy to be able to sing it here. Thank you very much.
そして『特急しらさぎ』は、もう難しかった！すごい難しかったんだから！
And "Tokkyu Shirasagi" was just so hard! It was incredibly difficult!
だってさ、1番と2番さ、
Because, you know, the first and second verses,
あのサビの振りも違うしさ、めっちゃ難しかったよ！
the choreography for the chorus is different. It was so hard!
≠ME（イコラブ）さんの曲は毎回難しいけど、すごい踊ってて楽しいでございますね。はい。
Songs by ≠ME (and =LOVE) are always hard, but they're so much fun to dance to. Yes.
そして『ぱぴぷぺぽPOP』。
And then "PaPiPuPePo POP".
これ、あのー、ずっとこうやってるから、すごい疲れて、あの、汗だくになった。
Since we're doing this the whole time, it's exhausting and I got all sweaty.
すごかったよ、練習中の時も汗だくすぎて、
It was intense. Even during practice I was too sweaty,
「ちょっと待って、ちょっと疲れた...」とか言って、
saying "Wait a sec, I'm a bit tired..."
みんなでわちゃわちゃしながら練習もしましたけど、すごい楽しかったでございます。
We had fun practicing all together like that, though.
そして、ちょっと紹介できてなかった、こちらのステージ！じゃーん！かわいい！
And, I hadn't been able to introduce it yet, this stage! Tada! It's cute!
すごい可愛くね、作っていただきました。
They made it look so cute for me.
アイドルソングたちばかりなので
Since they're all idol songs,
「アイドルステージ」っていう感じにしてくださいって言って
I asked for an "Idol Stage" kind of feeling.
こんな感じになりましたよ
And it turned out like this!
提灯もあるけどさ すごい主張しすぎないというか
There are lanterns too, but they aren't too overpowering.
パステルなピンクとか… これ色変わるんですけど
Like this pastel pink... the colors actually change.
すごい可愛い感じにしてくれて
They made it look so cute.
風船もこれ 色変わるんですよね 実はね
The balloons change color too, actually.
ちょっとその辺も注目していただきたいなと思いますね
I'd like you to pay attention to that too.
めっちゃ可愛いでしょ？
It's super cute, right?
後で一個だけ持って帰らせてもらおうかなと思います
I think I'll take one home with me later.
あとね みんな気づいてなかったかなと思うんですけど
Also, I wonder if everyone noticed...
あのね、まつりすがいるわけですよ！
See, the Matsuris are here!
1期生の周年ライブの時にはいなかったんですよ
They weren't here for the 1st gen anniversary live.
エビフライオンがいたの、代わりに
Ebifrion was here instead.
他のさ はあとんとかはさ ちゃんとハアトンとしていたのに
Other listeners like Haaton were there as Haatons,
リスナーさんの姿でいたのに
appearing in their listener forms,
まつりだけまつりすがいなくて エビフライオンだったんで
but for me, there were no Matsuris, only Ebifrions.
今回 よかったね これ
I'm glad they're here this time.
ということで 早速次の曲いきましょうか
So, let's head straight to the next song.
次もアイドルソングでございますよ
The next one is an idol song too!
それでは聴いてください、「IDOL SONG」
Please listen to "IDOL SONG."
ねえアイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol
すっごい愛をあげたい
I want to give you incredible love
このいのちの使い方を
With the way I use this life of mine,
君に愛されたい
I want to be loved by you
はーい！
Hi!
えくぼは恋の落とし穴
My dimples are love's pitfall
夢中にさせちゃうぞ
I'll make you crazy about me
埼玉県からきました
I came from Saitama Prefecture
フレッシュレモンになりたいのー
I want to be a Fresh Lemon!
ファンの方が恋人です
My fans are my lovers
真面目なアイドル
A serious idol
真面目にアイドル
An idol seriously
年中無休
Available year-round
24時間ずっと笑顔で
Smiling 24 hours a day
うさちゃんぴー
Usachan-pii!
はい！ あなたの心に ホッピング！
Hi! Hopping into your heart!
あなたのハートに アクセスします！
I'm accessing your heart!
みんなの ドキドキに シュートします！
I'm shooting into everyone's pounding hearts!
なんでもいいから レスポンスください！
Give me a response, anything at all!
ハゲ気味の 皆様！
Everyone who's a bit balding!
よし！ 今日も可愛い！
Right! Cute again today!
小指ー！
Pinky finger!
ねえアイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol
ずっとは わからないけど
I don't know if it'll be forever,
幸せに 満ちてる シャンプーの香り 見つけたの
but I found the scent of shampoo full of happiness
歌で人の気持ち
So I can make people's hearts...
明るくできるように
...brighter with my songs,
きっと 人生に くじけてる人が いると思うから
because I'm sure there are people discouraged by life.
はい！ 好きでいいよ！
Hi! It's okay to love me!
はい！ もっと簡単に！
Hi! Keep it simple!
はい！ 好きでいいよ！
Hi! It's okay to love me!
はい！ もっと叫べ Yeah!
Hi! Shout it louder, yeah!
はい！ 好きでいいよ！
Hi! It's okay to love me!
はい！ めちゃくちゃ 話すのが苦手
Hi! I'm really bad at talking
可愛い自分 気持ち悪い
A cute me is gross
世界のルールを 歌って踊って 破壊する
Singing and dancing to destroy the world's rules
燃える倉庫 燃える髪の毛
Burning warehouse, burning hair
見た目は純白 中身は真っ黒
White on the outside, pitch black on the inside
ちょっぴりおバカな 小さな巨人
A slightly stupid little giant
完・全・承・知
Full acknowledgment
見る事と 見る気を混ぜるだけ
Just mix seeing with the will to see,
あっという間に ミルキー
and in an instant, it's Milky
ちちんぷいぷい 魔法にかかれ
Abrakadabra, fall under my spell!
おっ かかっちゃった
Oh, you're under it now!
トイレなんて 行った事ないよ
I've never been to the toilet
ピンクのマシュマロが 出ます
Pink marshmallows come out of me
3時のおやつは マカロンがいい
My 3 PM snack should be macarons
ふわふわガール 目指し中
Aiming to be a fluffy girl
ねえアイドルが楽しい
Hey, being an idol is fun
いっぱい愛が 回ってる
So much love is going around
ステージから 見る景色が ずっと宝物さ
The view from the stage will always be my treasure
でもし君が
But if you ever...
死にたくなって しまっても
...feel like you want to die,
君が生きるための 幸せを あげられていたかな
I wonder if I was able to give you the happiness to live on
はい！ 好きでいいよ！
Hi! It's okay to love me!
はい！ もっと大胆に！
Hi! Be more bold!
はい！ 好きでいいよ！
Hi! It's okay to love me!
はい！ もっと叫べ Yeah!
Hi! Shout it louder, yeah!
はい！ 好きでいいよ！
Hi! It's okay to love me!
はい！ 360度 どこから見ても アイドル
Hi! From 360 degrees, an idol from anywhere
出席番号 ラッキーセブン
Attendance number: Lucky Seven
好きになっても いいですか？
Is it okay if I like you?
僕の妹が こんなに可愛い わけがない
My sister can't be this cute
ど・ぷりぷり ぴちぴちでしょ
I'm so bouncy and fresh, right?
こんにちは！ ギラギラ
Hello! Dazzling!
アセル・アイシテル・ランドセル
Panicking, loving you, school bag
今日あした あさっても
Today, tomorrow, and the day after
キラキラパワー 全開！
Sparkling power at full throttle!
頑張って行こう！
Let's do our best!
みんなの目線は いただきまゆゆ！
Capturing everyone's gaze, Itadaki-Mayuyu!
泣き虫で 甘えん坊な みんなの妹
A crybaby and spoiled, everyone's little sister
ねえアイドルが楽しい
Hey, being an idol is fun
いっぱい愛が 回ってる
So much love is going around
ステージから 見る景色が ずっと宝物さ
The view from the stage will always be my treasure
ずっと歌ってたら本物さ
If I keep singing, it'll become the real thing.
ねえ アイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol.
すごい愛をあげたい
I want to give you so much love.
この命の使い方を
How to use this life...
君に愛されていたい
...is that I want to be loved by you.
好きでいいよ もっと簡単に
It's okay to love me, more easily.
好きでいいよ もっと激しく
It's okay to love me, more intensely.
好きでいいよ もっと簡単に
It's okay to love me, more easily.
好きでいいよ もっと激しく
It's okay to love me, more intensely.
好きでいいよ もっと大胆に
It's okay to love me, more boldly.
好きでいいよ もっと激しく
It's okay to love me, more intensely.
好きでいいよ もっと大胆に
It's okay to love me, more boldly.
好きでいいよ もっと激しく
It's okay to love me, more intensely.
届け優しさ絆
Reach out, kindness and bonds,
キラキラ輝け 頑張っていきましょう！
shine brightly, let's do our best!
ショイ！
Sore!
わあ！ びっくりしたでしょ
Whoa! You were surprised, weren't you?
今日の私が昨日より可愛いなんて
That I'm even cuter today than I was yesterday.
ぎゅーちゅぎゅーちゅぎゅってして
Squeeze, kiss, squeeze, kiss, give me a squeeze.
次の流行りは 次の自撮り
The next trend is the next selfie,
困らないようにしっとかなくちゃ
gotta stay informed so I don't miss out.
でもぎゅってしたら大爆発
But if you squeeze me, it's a big explosion!
散りたい散りたい知りたくない
I wanna scatter, I wanna scatter, I don't wanna know.
知りたくない ずっと閉じてたら
I don't wanna know, if I keep them closed forever,
すべて なぜなぜわからないだらけのコスワンダーランド
everything is a 'why?' in this 'Cos-Wonderland' of unknowns.
私 ちっちっちっちっ ぎゅー私
Me, chi-chi-chi-chi, squeeze me!
ちっちっちっちっ ぎゅー私
Chi-chi-chi-chi, squeeze me!
ぎゅー！
Squeeze!
ここ最年少 未来最年少
The youngest here, the youngest in the future.
ここ最大量 未来カステラ
Maximum amount here, future Castella.
未来ちらちら 福袋みたい
Future flickering, like a lucky bag.
好きな色が見えたから これにしよ！
I saw my favorite color, so I'll pick this one!
たまとカステラ イェーイ！
Tama and Castella, Yay!
移住しないならしちゃうじね
If you don't move in, I'll just do it.
間違っても可愛くなれるじね
Even if I make a mistake, I can still be cute.
一番可愛い時に死にたいなら
If you want to die when you're at your cutest,
全然死なないね
you'll never die at all.
私 ちっちっちっちっ
Me, chi-chi-chi-chi,
ぎゅー私 ちっちっちっちっ
squeeze me, chi-chi-chi-chi.
死んでる暇ない可愛さ言いたい
I want to say, cuteness has no time for dying.
ここ最年少 未来最年少
The youngest here, the youngest in the future.
今無敵子 未来全部入り
Invincible girl now, everything in the future.
好きな瞳が好きな私で
With the eyes I love, being the me I love,
ひたすらすごく素敵な女の子
I'm just a very wonderful girl,
なんだもん
that's what I am.
「何歳になっても可愛いね」じゃないの
It's not 'You're cute no matter how old you get'.
こっちは努力して可愛いやってんの
I'm putting in the effort to be cute!
何十何歳だったって可愛いの
I'm cute even if I'm decades old.
本当はそんなの当たり前だもん
In fact, that's just common sense.
言わせないでよ そっちから言って
Don't make me say it, you say it first.
「今日も可愛いね」でしょ？
It's 'You're cute today too,' right?
今日も可愛いね！ 今日も可愛いね！
Cute today too! Cute today too!
可愛いね！ 可愛い！
So cute! Cute!
今日も可愛い！ 今日も可愛い！
Cute today! Cute today!
私 今日も可愛いね！
I'm cute today too, aren't I!
よし、今日も可愛いぞ！
Alright, I'm cute today too!
未来ちらちら 降りな追い風
Future flickering, descending tailwind.
覗き見しては元に戻して
Peeking in and then putting it back.
未来ちらちら 怖いからこそ
Future flickering, precisely because it's scary,
今を燃やして今日に行きたい
I want to burn the present and go into today.
ここ最年少 未来最年少
The youngest here, the youngest in the future.
ここ最大量 未来カステラ
Maximum amount here, future Castella.
未来ちらちら 福袋みたい
Future flickering, like a lucky bag.
好きな色が見えたから これにしよ！
I saw my favorite color, so I'll pick this one!
たまとカステラ イェーイ！
Tama and Castella, Yay!
ちゅーぎゅー ちゅーぎゅー
Chu-gyu, chu-gyu.
ちゅーぎゅー ぎゅーぎゅー ぎゅーぎゅー
Chu-gyu, gyu-gyu, gyu-gyu.
カステラー！
Castella!
君に恋な恋のエスオーエス
Falling for you, a SOS of love.
ずっと胸が苦しいです
My heart has been aching forever.
早くレスキュー 好きのテレパシー
Quick, rescue me with a telepathy of love.
早く気づいて
Please notice me soon.
初めて出会った時から
Since the first time we met,
ハートが震えてたんだよ
my heart has been trembling.
無意識に意識しちゃう
I consciously notice you unconsciously.
この感じはきっと急上昇で
This feeling is definitely rapidly rising.
求め合うだけで顔が熱いの
Just seeking each other makes my face hot.
話しかけられて頭がパニック
My head panics whenever you talk to me.
キミにFall in love 恋のSOS
I'm falling in love with you, love's SOS
ずっと胸が苦しいんです
I've been feeling pained in my chest forever
ハヤクRescue
Hurry, Rescue!
「好き」のテレパシーに早く気づいて！
Please notice the telepathy of 'I love you' soon!
初めて出逢ったときから
Ever since we first met
ハートが震えてたんだよ
My heart has been trembling
無意識に意識しちゃう
I'm conscious of you without meaning to
この感じはきっと (重症です)
This feeling is definitely (a serious condition)
目と目合うだけで顔が熱いの
My face gets hot just from our eyes meeting
話しかけられて頭がパニック
My head goes into a panic when you talk to me
ドキドキし過ぎて会話続かない...
I'm pounding too much, the conversation won't continue...
キミが好きな音楽や
The music you like
映画のことリサーチして
And the movies I've researched
SNS見るたびに
Every time I look at SNS
「いいね」押すの アピールだよ
Giving a 'Like' is my way of showing it
真夜中に君のこと考えて
Thinking about you in the middle of the night
悶々としながら枕蹴りした
I kicked my pillow while brooding
明日はどの服着ていこうかな
What clothes should I wear tomorrow?
君想うだけでなんか照れる
Just thinking about you makes me blush
キミにFall in love 恋のSOS
I'm falling in love with you, love's SOS
ずっと胸が苦しいんです
I've been feeling pained in my chest forever
ハヤクRescue
Hurry, Rescue!
「好き」のテレパシーに早く気づいて！
Please notice the telepathy of 'I love you' soon!
これはFall in love 恋のSOS
This is falling in love, love's SOS
もっと君に近づきたい
I want to get closer to you
終わらせて 片想い My heart
Let my unrequited love end, my heart
全部抱きしめて
Hold me completely
生まれたてのドキドキを 響かせよう
Let's make the excitement of being newborn resound
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
The best time, with the best companions
キラメキに乗って☆ (イェーイ!)
Riding on the sparkle☆ (Yeah!)
覚えてるかな? 最初の歌
Do you remember? Our first song
私 声が震えていた
My voice was trembling
あの日から続く未来は
The future that continues from that day
みんなと掴んだキセキだよ
Is the miracle I grasped with everyone
もっと もっと もっと
More, more, more
加速するハート
My heart is accelerating
重ねた手はギュッと 離さずに
Let's go, holding our stacked hands tightly without letting go
一人じゃない 描きたすときめき
I'm not alone, the excitement I draw more of
振り向くことなく まっすぐに
Without looking back, straight ahead
行くよ！（いこう！）夢見る空へ
Let's go! (Let's go!) Towards the sky of our dreams
笑いあったことや
The times we laughed together,
尽きそうにない思い出いっぱいなのに
Even though there are so many memories that never end
あっという間の日々
The days went by in a flash
上書きじゃなくて
Not by overwriting them
なまえつけてハート
Give it a name, Heart
どれも全部大事って 言えるはず
I should be able to say everything is important
みんなのためが力になる
Being for everyone becomes my strength
今日も賑やかすぎるくらい
Today is also almost too lively
笑顔が止まらない
The smiles won't stop
思いは膨らんでいく
Feelings are expanding
重ねて今ギュッと噛み締めた
Overlapping, now I firmly savored it
独り占め時間 カウントダウンは広がる
Monopolizing time, the countdown expands
風を感じたら真っ直ぐに
If you feel the wind, go straight
行くよ 夢見る空へ
Let's go, to the dreaming sky
あすいろClearSky
Asuiro ClearSky
背伸びしては手を伸ばす 憧れの
Standing on tiptoes and reaching out...
行き先示す星になろう
to the yearning, let's be the star showing the way.
近づくその度に 手を差し伸べ合えたら
If we can reach out whenever we get closer,
すぐに届くはずさ
it should reach us soon.
そっと踏み出した 小さな勇気が
The small courage I softly stepped forward with,
もう消えないように繋げよう
let's connect it so it never disappears again.
不安も愛しさも大切に抱きしめて
Embracing both anxiety and love dearly,
共に行くよ 目を合わせて 3, 2, 1
we'll go together, eye to eye, 3, 2, 1.
晴れ渡る希望へ
Towards the clear hope,
飛び出せるよ 突き抜けていく
I can jump out, piercing through.
僕たちの透き通る決意今
Our transparent determination, right now.
まだまだ止められないよ
It can't be stopped yet.
ありきたりな日常こそ ときめきに変えて もっと
Turn even mundane daily life into excitement, more.
僕たちがいつまでも
Because we will,
背中を押すから
always be pushing your back.
憧れの舞台立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams.
らしく輝きたい
I want to shine like myself.
時に涙して また笑い合いたい
Sometimes crying, wanting to laugh together again.
同じ未来を見たい
I want to see the same future.
あの夢手にしたい
I want to hold that dream.
踏み出そう 奇跡の一歩を
Let's take it, the first step of a miracle.
生き切らして夢追いかけたい
I want to chase dreams until I'm out of breath.
ワクワク止まらない
The excitement won't stop.
ゾクゾク超えていく 世界に見せてあげる
Going beyond the shivers, I'll show the world.
アクセスしてみたい
I want to try accessing.
後悔なんてここにない
There's no regret here.
それぞれ違った心で 作るわ
We'll make it with our different hearts.
はい、ということで、ホロライブ... ホロライブメドレー、自分んの事務所なのに、でした！
So, that was the hololive... hololive medley, even though it's my own agency!
いやどうだった？なんか激エモだったんじゃないですか？
How was it? It was super emotional, wasn't it?
そしてね、この衣装は初めて貰ったアイドル衣装なんでございますよね
And you know, this costume is the first idol costume I ever received.
なんかあの時を思い出して、なんかすごいジーンときてしまいますわね
Remembering that time, it really tugs at the heartstrings.
そう、まつりはね、元々そのアイドルデビューじゃなかったんですよホロライブって
Right, Matsuri didn't actually start as an idol in hololive.
でこの衣装貰って、よしアイドルとして頑張るぞというね、気持ちを改めて思い出し
Receiving this costume reminded me of that feeling of 'I'll do my best as an idol'.
頑張っていこうかなという気持ちでございます
And I feel motivated to keep giving it my all.
はい、そしてそして、今回も！
Yes, and and, this time too!
誕生日グッズでございまーす！やったー！
It's birthday goods! Yay!
嬉しい、ということで、一つずつ紹介していきます
I'm so happy, so I'll introduce them one by one.
まずは、こちら！ドドン！
First, here it is! Ta-da!
「薄すぎっ！おっぱいマウスパッド」
"Too Thin! Oppai Mouse Pad"
あ、おっぱいマウスパッド！やったー！
Ah, an oppai mouse pad! Yay!
イラストは、えく先生！
Illustrated by Eku-sensei!
まつり待望のね、マウスパッドでございますよ
It's the mouse pad Matsuri has been waiting for.
もう、あのちなみに言うと、膨らみは、ないです
By the way, there is no bulge.
普通のマウスパッドとなっております
It's a regular mouse pad.
こうやって、あの、癒やすことは、ちょっと難しいんですが、
It’s a bit hard to heal you directly like this, but...
まぁちょっとガチ照れな
Well, she looks genuinely embarrassed,
きゅっ、みたいな感じなのでね、あの、もう心から癒やされていくという感じで
and has that 'squeeze' feel, so you'll be healed from the bottom of your heart.
はい、どうですか？素晴らしいことでございましょう！
Right? Isn't it wonderful!
そして、続いてこちら！
And next is this!
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
ランダムアクリルキーホルダー！
Random Acrylic Keychains!
なんと、夏色まつり先生のね、描き下ろしでございますよ！
Believe it or not, these are newly drawn by Natsuiro Matsuri-sensei herself!
ランダムアクリルキーホルダー。
Random Acrylic Keychains.
まつりがね、グッズのイラスト描くって、なかなか無いでございますから、
It's quite rare for Matsuri to draw illustrations for merchandise,
すごい愛情込めて書きました。もうちゅちゅちゅっ、ってしながら書いたので、
so I drew them with lots of love. I drew them with lots of 'mwah' sounds,
是非ね、全種類コンプリートしてみてください！
so please try to complete the whole set!
そして続いて、こちら！
And next up is this!
まつりちゃんのぬいぐるみ、サブカルジャージ衣装バージョン、でございます！
Matsuri-chan plushie, Subculture Jersey Outfit version!
キービジュのね、イラストと同じサブカルジャージの衣装の、なんと、ぬいが登場しちゃいますよ！
The plushie in the same subculture jersey from the key visual is here!
キービジュのように、おすおすすることは、ちょっと現実だと叶わないけど、
While 'pushing' like in the visual isn't possible in reality,
ぬいなら、ぬいならできちゃう！ということで、是非ね、たくさん可愛がって、
you can do it with a plushie! So please cherish it,
いろんなところに連れて行ってあげてください。
and take it with you everywhere.
さらに、こちら！
Furthermore, look at this!
まつりすマグカップ！
Matsurisu Mug!
みんなには、マグカップになってもらいました。
I've turned all of you into mugs.
どんな罪を犯して、こんな姿になっちまったんだ…って感じでございますが、
It's like, 'What sin did I commit to end up like this?' but...
まぁ自分なのでね、あの、これが俺の姿か、と思いながら、使っていただけたらなと思います。
Well, it's you, so please use it while thinking, 'So this is my form now.'
まつりちゃんも使わせていただきます！
Matsuri-chan will be using one too!
最後に、ボイス！
Lastly, the voice pack!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
シチュエーションボイス、「逆襲のまつりす」。
Situation Voice: 'Matsurisu's Counterattack'.
なんだ、「逆襲のまつりす」ってなんだ！？
What is 'Matsurisu's Counterattack' anyway?!
はい、今回ね、キービジュのシチュエーションに至るまでのストーリーが、ここに詰まっちゃってますので、
Well, the story leading up to the key visual's situation is packed in here,
どんなシチュエーションなのか、ちょっと気になる方は是非、ゲットしてみてください！
so if you're curious about the situation, please get it!
そして、
And...
フルセットを購入いただいた方、全員に！直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきちゃいます！
everyone who purchases the full set will get a postcard with a handwritten signature & foil-stamped message!
ちょっとね、来年は直筆やるか、ちょっと未定でございますので、
I'm not sure if I'll do handwritten ones next year,
是非ね、ぜひぜひぜひぜひ、全員に書かせていただきますので！
so I'll be writing for everyone, so please, please get it!
初めてなんですよ、それも。全員にサイン書くの初めてだから、
It's a first for me. The first time signing for everyone,
是非、手に入れてください。来年やるかわかんないからね。
so please get it. I don't know if I'll do it next year.
さらにですね、
Furthermore...
タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、2024年9月から発売された、ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが１枚ついてきちゃいますよ！
as a full set bonus for the Talent Premium Goods, you'll get a card for the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME!
まつりはね、前回のグッズでちょっと特典に、ついてなかったので、今回、ついてくるよ！って感じになっております。
Matsuri wasn't included in the previous goods' bonus, but this time, I'm in!
えー、同封する、同封であってるよね、日本語。
Um, 'enclosed'... that's the right Japanese word, right?
はい、ホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入された、お客様…おにょにょ…
Yes, for customers who purchase from the hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP...
あ、
Ah...
お客様のみの対象となっておりますので、よろしくお願いします。
it's only for those customers, so please keep that in mind.
特典につくのは、ゲームで１枚だけ使用でき、推しをアピールできるキーカード、
The bonus is a key card you can use in the game to show off your favorite,
推しホロメンカードでございます。
the Oshi holomen Card.
そして、そして、そして！さらにでございますよ！
And, and, and! There's even more!
まだある！
There's still more!
アルバム！
The Album!
デデデデデデデ！
Dururururu!
なんとまつりちゃん、ファーストアルバム、「Chasing the Dream - スポットライトは放課後に」が、
Matsuri-chan's first album, 'Chasing the Dream - Spotlight is After School'...
なんと本日！11月1日、受注開始でございます！
is available for pre-order starting today, November 1st!
パンパカパーン！
Fanfare!
まつりちゃん初のオリジナル楽曲、「君と眺める夏の花」を始め、
Starting with Matsuri-chan's first original song, 'Summer Flowers Gazing with You',
これまでに配信リリースしてきた作品の他、
it includes previously released digital works,
じんさん始め豪華作曲陣が、書き下ろしてくださった新曲も収録しちゃってますよ！
plus new songs written by Jin and other amazing composers!
全14曲の超ボリューミーなアルバムになっているので、ぜひ手に入れちゃってください。
It's a super voluminous 14-track album, so please get your hands on it.
コンセプトはね、アイドルのまつりちゃんと、普段の女子高生のまつりちゃんの、こう両面みたいな、
The concept is both sides of Matsuri-chan: the idol and the high school girl,
両方が楽しめるようなね、アルバムになってます。
so you can enjoy both in this album.
形態は２つありまして、
There are two versions available:
完全生産限定盤と、通常盤をご用意しております。
the Limited First Press Edition and the Standard Edition.
完全生産限定盤はですね、
The Limited First Press Edition...
セパレートタイプのオリジナルカレンダーが、ついてきちゃいますよ！
comes with a separate-type original calendar!
そして、
And...
両形態に、封入特典として、
as an enclosed bonus for both editions,
まつりちゃんからの複製お手紙が、入っています。
a replica letter from Matsuri-chan is included.
ただし、
However...
数量限定のランダムでですね、
in a limited random quantity,
複製お手紙の代わりに、直筆お手紙がもらえちゃう案内が、封入されていますので、
instead of the replica, there's a notice on how to get a handwritten letter,
ぜひぜひゲットしちゃってください！
so please get it!
以上、アルバム情報でした！
That's all for the album info!
そしてなんと！
And what's more!
アルバムに収録する新曲のうち一曲をですね
One of the new songs included in the album...
本日、この後、披露しちゃいます！
...I'll be performing it today, right after this!
タイトルは...
The title is...
ウーニャカ ニャニャニャ！
U-NYAKA NYA NYA NYA!
作曲はですね、かいりきベアさんに作曲いただきました！
It was composed by Kairiki Bear!
めちゃめちゃ可愛い！
It's super cute!
MVもですね、この後プレミア公開ありますので
The MV will also have a premiere after this,
0時から、あの、楽曲リリースもありますので
and the digital release is at midnight, so...
あの、是非よろしくお願いしますね。プレミア公開も一緒に見ようね。
...please check it out. Let's watch the premiere together!
はい！
Okay!
じゃあちょっと着替えてきますので、ちょっとここで待ってて
Well, I'm going to change now, so please wait here.
ワクワクって言いながらね、あのゲストパートと同じように
Excitedly, okay? Just like during the guest segment...
ワクワクって言いながら待っててください。
...please wait while saying "Waku-waku!"
じゃあ行ってきまーす！
Well, I'm off!
ワクワク！ワクワク！
Waku-waku! Waku-waku!
ウーニャカ
U-NYAKA
作詞・作曲：かいりきベア 編曲：UtopiLyric
Lyrics/Composition: Kairiki Bear, Arrangement: UtopiLyric
真夜中にトケタ 感情は爪立てて
Emotions dissolved in the middle of the night, claws bared
檻から見慣れた 世界は牙向いて
The familiar world from the cage bares its fangs
真夜中見かねた 感情は飢えた目で
Emotions unable to watch in the middle of the night, with hungry eyes
軽やかに逃げた 優しさ求めて
Lightly escaped, seeking kindness
「愛されたい」の想い 愛されないの Give me
The feeling of "wanting to be loved," but not being loved, give me
「愛してる」も重い 愛さえないの？もういい？
Is "I love you" too heavy? Is there no love left? Is it enough?
愛情結晶頂戴 あなたを見てるのじゃ
Give me the crystal of affection, I'm watching you
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おねだり
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, begging
さあ手懐けてよ もっとめいっぱい
Now, tame me, more, to the fullest
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おでかけ？
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, going out?
しがみついて どこも行かせない！
Clinging on, I won't let you go anywhere!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nya u-nyan-nyan
甘いキャンディ頂戴な
Give me sweet candy
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nya u-nyan-nyan
ハッピーライフ頂戴な
Give me a happy life
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nya u-nyan-nyan
叱らないで頂戴な
Please don't scold me
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nya u-nyan-nyan
ほんとの「好き」頂戴な
Give me your true "love"
縄張り土足で 感情丸出しで
Trampling over territory, emotions laid bare
幸せになれた 未来が牙向いて
The future that could have been happy bares its fangs
突き放さないでいて 切り捨てず傍で
Don't push me away, stay by my side without cutting me off
お傍で お傍で お傍で見ているのじゃ
By your side, by your side, I'm watching you from by your side
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン お願い
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, please
さあ頭撫でて もっとぜーいっっぱい
Now, stroke my head, more, to the absolute fullest
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おあずけ？
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, on hold?
甘えて泣いて 此処に居させて！
Spoiling, crying, let me stay here!
ニャンニャカ言ったって伝わんない？
Does saying "Nyan-nyaka" not get through to you?
どーしたってこーしたって寂しいの
No matter what I do, I'm lonely
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おもいっきり
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, with all my might
あざとい声わざと聞かせる
Letting you hear my flirtatious voice on purpose
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おねだり
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, begging
さあ手懐けてよ もっとめいっぱい
Now, tame me, more, to the fullest
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おやすみ？
Nyan-nyaka rin-rin-rin, good night?
しがみついて 今夜寝かせない！
Clinging on, I won't let you sleep tonight!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nya u-nyan-nyan
甘いキャンディ頂戴な
Give me sweet candy
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nya u-nyan-nyan
ハッピーライフ頂戴な
Give me a happy life
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nya u-nyan-nyan
抱きしめて頂戴な
Please hold me tight
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン
U-nyaka nyan-nya u-nyan-nyan
ほんとの「好き」頂戴な
Give me your true "love"
アイドル革命進行中！ ～今日の主役は夢の途中～
Idol Revolution in Progress! ~Today's Protagonist is Mid-Dream~